<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>classification on Skylar Trigueiro</title>
    <link>skylartrigueiro.com/categories/classification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in classification on Skylar Trigueiro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="skylartrigueiro.com/categories/classification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Facial Recognition (Work in Progress)</title>
      <link>skylartrigueiro.com/portfolio/facialrecognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>skylartrigueiro.com/portfolio/facialrecognition/</guid>
      <description>Facial Recognition (Work in progress) This project is about training a Siamese neural network to determine if two photos are of the same person.
Data The data used to train the model is the &amp;ldquo;Yale Face Databse&amp;rdquo; which can be found at http://vision.ucsd.edu/content/yale-face-database
References 1.This project started as a project in the Udemy course &amp;ldquo;Pytorch: Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence&amp;rdquo;, which I highly recommend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Cyber Attack Classifier</title>
      <link>skylartrigueiro.com/portfolio/cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>skylartrigueiro.com/portfolio/cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>Overview The goal of this project is to develop a classifier to detect cyber attacks over a wifi network. Since the cost of incorrectly classifying normal activity as a cyber attack is less than the cost of classifying a cyber attack as normal activity, then I will favor the model which has a higher recall percentage in cyber attack categories.
Data The data from this project is sourced from the AWID project (http://icsdweb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Image Claissifier, Cifar 10</title>
      <link>skylartrigueiro.com/portfolio/cifar10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>skylartrigueiro.com/portfolio/cifar10/</guid>
      <description>Cifar-Image Classification Overview In this notebook I am creating an image classifier for the Cifar10 dataset which has an accuracy, precision, and recall of 91%. The Cifar10 dataset consists of 60k 32x32 pixel photos, of which 50k in the training set and 10k were used in the test set. The images are of:
airplanes automobiles birds cats deer dogs frogs horses ships trucks  I&amp;rsquo;m accomplishing this by using a convolutional neural network with a custom architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>skylartrigueiro.com/portfolio/kagglefrauddetection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>skylartrigueiro.com/portfolio/kagglefrauddetection/</guid>
      <description>IEEE-CIS Fraud Detection Kaggle Competition Overview For my first Kaggle competition, I developed a model for detecting fraudulent credit/debit card transactions. Teams were asked to submit probability predictions on a provided test set and the winning team was decided based on which team had the submission with the highest ROC-AUC score. I, as a solo competitor, placed 1598 out of 6381 teams with a ROC-AUC score of 0.924103. I accomplished this by creating an ensemble of lightGBM models.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
