<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Skylar Trigueiro&#39; Website on Skylar Trigueiro</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Skylar Trigueiro&#39; Website on Skylar Trigueiro</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 Disruption of Data Science Hiring</title>
      <link>/portfolio/coviddisruptsdatascience/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/coviddisruptsdatascience/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Overview Data Job Growth Salary Locations Big Companies 2020 Projections Conclusion References  Overview This project has two purposes. First, I would like to see what effect COVID-19 has had on data science job hiring in 2020. Second, I would like to gather some insight on when and where recent graduates should look in order to get their first job.
Data The data for this project was scraped from the website h1bdata.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic Stock Trading (Work in Progress)</title>
      <link>/portfolio/algorithmictrading/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/algorithmictrading/</guid>
      <description>Algorithmic Trading (Work in progress) This project is about trying to develop an intelligent way of following stock market trends to improve returns compared to buying and holding onto stock. However, I seem to have shown that it&amp;rsquo;s easier and better to simply buy stock and hold stock than it is to try and time the market.
Data I will use the performance of large companies contained in the S&amp;amp;P 500 to predict trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facial Recognition (Write Up in Progress)</title>
      <link>/portfolio/facialrecognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/facialrecognition/</guid>
      <description>Facial Recognition (Work in progress) This project is about training a Siamese neural network to determine if two photos are of the same person.
Data The data used to train the model is the &amp;ldquo;Yale Face Databse&amp;rdquo; which can be found at http://vision.ucsd.edu/content/yale-face-database
References  This project started as a project in the Udemy course &amp;ldquo;Pytorch: Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence&amp;rdquo;, which I highly recommend.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cipher Decryption</title>
      <link>/portfolio/cypherdecryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/cypherdecryption/</guid>
      <description>Cipher Decryption Please see the github respository for more details about the model.
Overview In this project I am building a cipher decrypter for simple ciphers in the english language. An example of a simple cipher would be map of the form:
{a:b, b:c, c:d, &amp;hellip;, z:a}
so that the message &amp;ldquo;abc&amp;rdquo; is transformed into &amp;ldquo;bcd&amp;rdquo;. To solve this problem, I will be building a genetic trigram model. I decided to use a trigram model instead of a bigram model because &amp;ldquo;qu&amp;rdquo; is more common than &amp;ldquo;ju&amp;rdquo; and so words that should be decrypted into &amp;ldquo;just&amp;rdquo; turn into &amp;ldquo;qust&amp;rdquo; because of &amp;ldquo;qu&amp;rdquo; being more likely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Cyber Attack Classifier</title>
      <link>/portfolio/cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>Overview The goal of this project is to develop a classifier to detect cyber attacks over a wifi network. Since the cost of incorrectly classifying normal activity as a cyber attack is less than the cost of classifying a cyber attack as normal activity, then I will favor the model which has a higher recall percentage in cyber attack categories.
Data The data from this project is sourced from the AWID project (http://icsdweb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a new Website</title>
      <link>/blog/first-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 12:14:34 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/first-blog/</guid>
      <description>For a long time this website has had a couple of links to contact me, but those days are over.
Now I have a brand new Hugo website with a custom written theme complete with
 A homepage with more social links, and description of my skills An about page with description of who I am A portfolio page to showcase all my projects A blog  Why Hugo? The first question is why a site builder?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Image Claissifier, Cifar 10</title>
      <link>/portfolio/cifar10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/cifar10/</guid>
      <description>Cifar-Image Classification Overview In this notebook I am creating an image classifier for the Cifar10 dataset which has an accuracy, precision, and recall of 91%. The Cifar10 dataset consists of 60k 32x32 pixel photos, of which 50k in the training set and 10k were used in the test set. The images are of:
airplanes automobiles birds cats deer dogs frogs horses ships trucks  I&amp;rsquo;m accomplishing this by using a convolutional neural network with a custom architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fraud Detection</title>
      <link>/portfolio/kagglefrauddetection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/kagglefrauddetection/</guid>
      <description>IEEE-CIS Fraud Detection Kaggle Competition Overview For my first Kaggle competition, I developed a model for detecting fraudulent credit/debit card transactions. Teams were asked to submit probability predictions on a provided test set and the winning team was decided based on which team had the submission with the highest ROC-AUC score. I, as a solo competitor, placed 1598 out of 6381 teams with a ROC-AUC score of 0.924103. I accomplished this by creating an ensemble of lightGBM models.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
